MATT WORBY

SUMMARY

Experienced developer with several years of experience in backend development, Data Analysis, ETL, SQL and numerous development languages with a proficiency specifically in web languages (HTML/CSS/JavaScript). Passionate about design in UI/UX and especially software. Insatiable drive and curiosity to learn and grow into full-stack development. Significant experience working on teams in addition to excellent written and verbal communication skills and working with internal and external clients/customers to better understand and deliver projects to meet the needs of the business.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

https://github.com/mattworby (Github), https://mattworby-portfolio.vercel.app (Portfolio)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Story Book Brawl Tracker 2021

- Utilizing ElectronJS, created a card tracker for a small, indie video game, Story Book Brawl
- Transformed a traditional style window into an overlay so the user can see the game behind the application as well as added in-game assets to stylistically fit
- Grabbed information from a user created JSON API to track specific cards
- Read in from a game generated log file and deciphered it in order to track game history of all the users participating and interacting with the users client

Cat Game 2020-2021

- Used VanillaJS to send and receive messages to and from the back end and display it to the
 user. HapiJS was used as an API to allow the sending of messages between the front and
 backend Node.JS was utilized on the backend to then communicate to the database and
 interpret input from the Twitch chat bot
- HTML/CSS used to provide basic structures and styling for the User's interface and the game's UI The database used was Postgres as it was the simplest to set up on the AWS EC2 Redhat server. Other tools used are Twitch Extensions as the user interface and Asperite to draw pixel art

Skaterbot 2019-2021

- Created a chat bot in Node.JS for use on Discord by over 2000 active users
- Utilized a number of JSON APIs to act as databases to pull a large variety of information from weather, video game news, to random pictures of animals
- Worked with a Twitch API to display a message to the Discord server when specific Twitch streamers were active

Equation Calculator 2013-2015

- Created an Android app my Freshman year of college to deep dive into programming Java was used to provide the main functionality of the applications
- XML was utilized to provide the look and feel of the application

- The application had hundreds of formulas and equations in a wide range of Mathematics and Scientific fields
- The app had several thousand downloads before being removed from the Android App Market
 Performed Quality Assurance and bug fixing through multiple versions and updates
 Utilized Android Studio which is built on the Eclipse IDE

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst at Applied Systems, University Park, IL (remote) 2018-2021

- Used MSSQL to validate and cleanse client's data alongside adding customizations
- Updated/created SQL scripts to help strengthen the conversion process
- Built various internal tools in languages ranging from HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VBScript, and Batch Responsible for ETL conversions from outside/legacy software to Applied Software
- Communicated with clients both internally and externally to understand their needs
- Utilized documentation to provide quality assurance for each conversion
- Communicated with a development team regarding bugs and quality assurance for internal applications

Programmer I at Kankakee Community College, Kankakee, IL 2016-2018

- Utilized Ellucian for data collection and reported on figures input into the system
- MSSQL was utilized to further validate findings and update any incongruities
- Various help desk tickets were completed using MSSQL in-between reporting periods
- Colleague Studio's proprietary language (SQL-like) was used to correct errors in the reporting software's code
- Reported student and faculty data to the ICCB (Illinois Community College Board)
- Relationships were established between departments to ensure the integrity of the reported data

EDUCATION

Southern Illinois University, bachelor's degree 2016 Major: Computer Science

Minor: Business Administration